What kind of guys gamble with the boss's money, swipe a killer's
Cadillac, and party on the mob's credit card?
Wise Guys is a comedy, crime film directed by Brian De Palma.
Harry Valentini and Moe Dickstein are both errand boys for the Mob.
When they lose $250,000, they are set up to kill each other.
But they run off to Atlantic City and comedy follows.
Harry Valentini, played by Danny DeVito.
Moe Dickstein, played by Joe Piscopo.
Bobby DiLea, played by Harvey Keitel.
Marco, played by Ray Sharkey.
Anthony Castelo, played by Dan Hedaya.
Frank "The Fixer" Acavano, played by Louis Albano.
Wise Guys is a 1986 American black comedy crime film directed by Brian De Palma and produced
by Aaron Russo from a screenplay written by George Gallo and Norman Steinberg.
It stars Danny DeVito and Joe Piscopo as two small-time mobsters from Newark, New Jersey, and
features Harvey Keitel, Ray Sharkey, Lou Albano, Dan Hedaya, and Frank Vincent.
De Palma later called it "a movie I wish I hadn't done...
The studio changed their minds and didn't want to make it.
They just wanted us to go away.
I should have just taken my money and walked instead of dealing
with a studio that didn't want to make the movie."
The film explores themes of gangster, mafia, horse racing.
The tone is lighthearted.